London, United Kingdom (+44) 7783602996 azfar.ghazian@gmail.com

Ghazian Azfar

Software Engineer

GitHub: ghazian Portfolio Site LinkedIn: ghazian

Software Engineer experienced in developing customer-focused applications and user-centered solutions with intuitive design. Currently building real-time sports data dashboards and visualizations for SaaS products, spanning front-end and back-end services.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages Python, JavaScript, TypeScript, Go

Databases PostgreSQL, DynamoDB, Redis / AWS Elasticsearch

Kubernetes, Django, Docker, AWS, Terraform (IaC), GraphQL, WebSockets, REST API **Back End**

Jest, Testing Library, Playwright Test

Web Development React, MUI, NextJS, TypeScript, Styled Components, Node. js, Remix, Zustand, Zod, Redux

Skills Clean Code, Extreme Programming, CI/CD (Github Actions) & Accessibility

WORK EXPERIENCE

Mid Software Engineer Jan 2024 — Present IMG Arena London, UK

- Developed and maintained a real-time, data-driven web platform showcasing over 65,000+ live sports events globally. Designed scalable solutions utilizing WebSockets for low-latency updates and REST APIs for data retrieval.
- Introduced design principles to create reusable components, ensuring consistent UI/UX design standards across 2 product lines. This improved the overall design and made it easy for team members of all skill levels to compose and extend components.
- Developed the company's first data and table visualization package, which includes a suite of customisable widgets and themes. This package is now used throughout the organization and externally.
- · Designed and implemented high-performance APIs in NodeJS, optimizing server-side data processing and achieving a 50% decrease in data retrieval speeds, along with API documentation in Docusaurus library.
- Successfully implemented and deployed Redis as an in-memory caching solution for heavy API calls and PostgreSQL for static data reducing response times by up to 200%.
- Mentored and onboarded graduate team members through a mentor buddy program, facilitating their integration into the team.

Junior Software Engineer IMG Arena

Jul 2022 - Jan 2024

London, UK

- · Leveraged Kubernetes health checks and Datadog metrics to ensure the resiliency and reliability of microservices. Created Datadog dashboards to monitor application health and configured monitors for alerts.
- Actively wrote tests, integration/unit with Jest and E2E tests with Playwright and Mock Service Worker (MSW), I also wrote our test environment through MSW, mocking WebSockets, GraphQL, REST API responses.
- Implemented state management in our React application to streamline network performance, resulting in a 40% decrease in latency across thousands of WebSocket messages, GraphQL and REST API integrations, ensuring a seamless user experience.
- Developed the applications CI/CD, ensuring that every branch on the latest commit triggers continuous integration for tests, UI deprecation, and network health.

Consulting Intern Sept 2018 — Dec 2018 Deloitte

Created a **Python** script to assess workflow documents and extract vital metrics resulting in a **2-hour reduction** in work.

• Facilitated workshops with VP/Manager level to uncover pain points and potential use-cases of the transformation program.

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Computer Science, University of Glasgow | Aggregate 2:1 Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science, University of Binus | Aggregate 2:1

Jan 2021 - Jan 2022 Sept 2015 - Jan 2020

PROJECTS

BIG DATA CORESET CONSTRUCTION IN K-MEANS PROBLEM

Jan 2022

Jakarta, IDN

Created a lightweight coreset construction for K-Means problem along with 3 algorithms based on the works of [1][2][3], to reduce the amount of space time complexities machines currently use when clustering K-Means problem of large data sets. Platforms - Python, NumPy, Matplotlib (data visualization), Pandas, Shell Scripting and Tensor Flow.

Other Projects include - Real time bike sharing web application with Flask; Using Artificial Intelligence to play Flappy Bird using Neural Network and Genetic Algorithms.